JOAO COSTA

WEB DEVELOPER





✓ joaoartursilvacosta@gmail.com

Porto, Portugal

https://joao-costaportfolio.netlify.app/

PROFILE

I'm an IT professional with 7 years experience in the areas of banking , Digital Marketing and E-commerce.

I love building things that live on the web and I'm passionate about using technology to build a better user experience for my customer. I'm highly motivated to provide legendary service to my customers and team mates

SKILLS

- React 18
- NodeJs
- TypeScript
- Tailwind CSS
- Styled Components
- Redux
- Jest Unit testing
- Next.js
- SASS
- mySQL
- MongoDb

EXPERIENCE

FULLSTACK LEAD DEVELOPER

Mi-gso PCub3d

2022 - Present

- Lead a team of 5 developers in building several applications to support PMO activities
- Developed a Redux like library based on Context API for state management of all applications

AWS

React Node JS

FREELANCE WEB DEVELOPER

Self-Employed 2021 - 2022

 Development of custom Ecommerce Platforms with Full featured shopping cart, Admin product management, Checkout process

(shipping, payment method, etc), PayPal / credit card integration, User profile with orders

• Custom Landing Pages development

Next.js Node JS MongoDb

WEB DEVELOPER

Natixis Portugal

2017 - 2021

- Built a client onboarding application praised by customers as a simple and effective tool to complete the onboarding process
- Built a client services dashboard for KYC process tracking praised by management for great user experience.
- Built a KYC dynamic form that allowed for vetting analysts to complete their analysis 30% faster
- Took charge of engineering an internal social network for employee skill and knowledge sharing. Implemented a first version with complements on build quality from end-users.

TELECOMS MASTER'S

Faculdade Engenharia do Porto

EDUCATION

ELECTRONIC ENGINEERING

Instituto Superior de Engenharia do

2016- Ongoing

Porto

2013-2016

.NET Core

Angular

React